水母免疫系统
绿色生物萤光
异常快速反应
诱发性细胞游走
再生能力的遗传基础
发现DNA片段
我企图制造人类再生能力
再生即是永生
组织硬化
防御功能
灵长类动物实验
猴子死亡  基因改造失败
因毒素致死
中和毒性
关键物种
蜥蜴/抗毒性
最高毒性质
继续灵长类动物实验
不可能抵抗每一种化学武器
There's simply no way to shield against every weaponized agent.
但我能加强人体细胞反应
Instead, I can make super-immune systems...
制造出超级免疫系统
by strengthening the human cellular response.
班纳  我知道你在做什么
Banner, I know where you're going.
但改造免疫系统既危险又愚蠢
But manipulating the immune system is dangerous and stupid.
总统的科学顾问说得很清楚
The president's science advisors made it absolutely clear...
不准进行人体实验
no human subjects.
基因改造有进展
大卫  我有好消息
David, I have wonderful news.
我怀孕了
I'm gonna have a baby.
基因遗传
我遗传给他什么?
你要什么?
What's it gonna be?
瞧  布鲁斯  你要恐龙吗?
Whoa, look at that, Bruce. Huh? Want a dinosaur?
我们大战一场
Let's have a little fight.
我才不怕你
You don't scare me.
好好吃的眼球
That's a delicious eyeball.
你是可怕的绿怪物
Ooh, you're big and green and scary.
我最大的恐惧成真了
一定要找到解药
I'm gonna run away.
布鲁斯  你受伤了
Bruce, you're hurt!
小杰打他  布鲁斯没还手
Jack hit him with the stick, but Bruce wouldn't hit him back.
他只是站着一直发抖
He just stood there, shaking.
好怪哦  他一声也不吭
Yeah, strange he didn't make a peep.
一般小孩会哭得死去活来
Any other kid would've wailed his head off.
布鲁斯就是这么地…
That's Bruce. He's like that.
压抑
He's just so... bottled up.
我在实验室找到人类血液样本
The samples we found in your lab... they were human blood.
你违反了规定
You've ignored protocol.
你无权干涉我的实验
You had no right snooping around in my lab.
这是我的事
That's my business.
错了  这是政府公事
Wrong, Banner. It's government business
你不准再做实验
and you're off the project.
全员注意  故障安全系统启动
Attention, all personnel. Fail-safe has been initiated.
半小时后清除伽玛辐射污染
Gamma decontamination will occur in 30 minutes!
立刻撤离
Evacuate immediately!
我重覆  立刻撤离
I repeat, evacuate immediately!
伊蒂
Edith?
怎么回事?
what's going on?
我们得谈谈  伊蒂
I gotta talk to you, Edith.
布鲁斯  留在这儿
Bruce, stay here.
你在干什么?
大卫  住手
David! No!
大卫  听我说
David, please stop it! No!
布鲁斯  快醒醒  儿子
Bruce.Bruce, wake up, son.
布鲁斯
Bruce. Bruce.
你又做了噩梦?
Another nightmare?
不晓得  我不记得了
I don't know.I don't remember.
嗨  妈
Hi, Mom.
你就要去上大学了
Already off to college.
我会很想你
Gonna miss you terribly.
我也会很想你
I'll miss you too.
来  过来
Please, come here.
看看你  你会成为伟大科学家
Look at you,Soon to be a great scientist.
也许吧  谁知道呢?
I guess.
我知道
I mean, who knows? I do.
你身上有什么… 很特别
There's something inside you... so special.
一种很了不起的能力
Some kind of greatness.
有一天你会让全世界知道
I'm sure someday you're gonna share it with the whole world.
柏克莱核能生化科技研究所
我觉得保全应该…
But as far as I'm concerned, security oughta be...
早安  柯兹勒博士
Good morning. Good morning, Dr. Krenzler.
我觉得应该要加强保全
Security oughta be beefed up.
这种地方一定要格外小心
In a place like this you can't be too careful.
就是今天了  你有没有睡?
Bruce! Big day.Did you sleep?
我可是睡不着
I didn't sleep.
我睡得还好  贝蒂在吗?
I slept okay.Is Betty here?
在啊
She's around.
老实说  你的头盔有够时髦
I really gotta say, seeing you in that stylin' head wear...
你嫌我的安全帽很丑?
You're implying something about my helmet?
你活像个呆瓜  谁也没你逊
You look like a massive nerd, even around other scientists.
你被她甩掉那天也戴这玩意吗?
Can I just ask... Were you wearing the helmet while she dumped you?
这头盔是保护我这颗重要大脑的  哈普
See, it protects my very important brain, Harper.
去准备样本吧
Go prep the samples.
我找到你了
I found you.
嗨  贝蒂
Hey. Betty.
我恨死他们了
I hate them.
我才刚到  你说谁?
Wait, I just got here. Who do we hate?
审查委员会  礼拜二要提案
The review board. We have to make a presentation on Tuesday. Ah.
你要跟我一起去
And you're gonna make it with me.
我该去吗?
You think I should? Yeah.
这种事你最在行
You're great with that stuff.
你只有谈到微生物和奈米微生物
You start talking about microbes and nanomeds,
才会稍微有点… 热情
you sound almost... passionate.
抱歉  这话太伤人
I'm sorry.That was rude.
没有人说一起工作很容易
Look, nobody expects this to be easy,
毕竟我们从前是那么… 亲密
us working together after being... so close.
我们有亲密过吗?
We were close?
要是我更…
Look, if I could be more...
那个  你知道的
whatever, you know...
别说了  不是你的错
It's not your fault. Really.
谁叫我老是找性情冷淡的男友
You're just a by-product of my inexplicable obsession with emotionally distant men.
总有一天我会释怀
I'll get over us.
那就好
Good for you.
这次审查让我很紧张
Anyway, I'm just really stressed about this review.
今天没有好的成果
If we don't get impressive results today,
礼拜二就很难说服他们
we're gonna have a really hard sell come Tuesday.
那就去干活吧
Well, then, let's go be impressive.
哈普?
Harper?
你好了就开始
Ready when you are.
开始吧
Let's hit it.
安检合格吗?
Are we passing inspection?
安全都没问题  倒数计时开始
Safeties all going green.Countdown's started.
释出奈米微生物
Nanomeds released.
奈米微生物释出
四秒钟
Four seconds.
奈米微生物完全释出
Okay, nanomeds fully dispersed.
好了  替小佛照伽玛射线吧
Okay, let's hit Freddie with the gamma radiation.
发射伽玛射线
Gamma exposure.
奈米微生物开始活动
Nanomeds now active.
奈米微生物在伤口处复制细胞
Nanomeds replicating cells on border.
成功了
It's working.
细胞修复和损坏误差值
Cell copy to disassemble ratio holding within one percent.
维持在百分之一内
奈米微生物活动失控
Imbalanced nanomed activity.
你想跟审查委员说
You wanna go to the review board on Monday and tell 'em...
我们发明杀青蛙的新方法?
we've developed a brand-new method for exploding frogs?
好啊  这一定有市场
Yeah, I think maybe there's a market for it.
搞不好会发生瘟疫
I mean, what if there's a plague?
你才喝一罐啤酒就醉了?
What have you had, Betty, like, one beer?
我只是说要是青蛙从天而降
I'm just sa... I'm just saying, you know,frogs start falling from the sky,
他们要去找谁?
who do they come to?
我们肯定会一炮而红
We'd be world-renowned.
父母一定会很骄傲
Make any parent proud.
你爸妈一定以你为傲
I bet they would be.
他们是希望我当科学家
They actually did want me to be a scientist.
我是说你的亲生父母
I mean, your birth parents.
我永远不会知道
Guess we'll never know.
你怎么一直不想知道他们的事
I don't understand why you don't want to find out about them.
他们早就死了
They're dead.
我什么都不记得他们就死了
They died before I can remember anything.
你为什么一直要追问?
Why do you always come back to this?
不晓得
Don't know.
我猜你的内心一定有什么秘密
I guess I figure there's more to you than you like to show.
你不可能天生就这么冷淡
I guess there couldn't be any less.
绕了半天又回到老问题
Right. So now we come full circle back to that.
你真行
Nice work, Betty.
葛伦
Glen. Hey.
你怎么没穿军服?
What happened to your uniform?
我换了工作
Oh, I, uh... I switched over.
我还是替你父亲做事
I'm still working with your father, but...
不过民间包商的工作更有趣
Well, you know, the military's subcontracting out all the most interesting work, and...
高薪也令人无法抗拒
Can't argue with a paycheck.
我负责基地所有的实验室
I basically run all the labs on the base now.
你看起来不错
you're looking good.
你是遗传工程专家
You're the genetics expert.
啊!大学时光
Ah, the good old college days.
你还好吗?
So, how's business?
你想要什么?
What do you want?
我就直话直说吧
All right, I'll cut to the chase.
听说你的研究工作很有意思
I've been hearing interesting things about what you guys are doing here.
你的分子机器有很多用途
Your little molecular machines have some incredible implications.
你不如到亚矽工作
How would you like to come work for Atheon?
薪水比你现在多十倍
Get paid 10 times as much as you earn now...
你也能拥有专利权
and own a piece of the patents.
你说一个字就行
You just have to say the word.
两个字  出去
Two words: The door.
将军?
General?
进来
Come in.
陶柏要你看这些
Talbot wanted you to see this, sir.
亚矽想买下一间实验室
It's about a lab Atheon is targeting for acquisition
搬到沙漠基地
and removal to desert base.
他怎么不去找国安局?
Why isn't it going through N.S.C.?
这跟你女儿有关
It, uh, concerns your daughter, sir.
班尼呢?
Hey, what happened to Benny?
他不值大夜班啦?
Is he not working the night shift anymore?
他死了  我是新来的工友
Benny's dead.I'm the new guy.
幸会了
Good to meet you.
彼此彼此
Same.
再拍一张
- Let's try another.
别拍了
Mmm, no. Stay here.
反正我很累
I look tired anyway.
你也很美
Yeah, but you look great.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
我一直在做噩梦
It's these dreams, Doctor.
好可怕哦
I keep having them, and they're terrible.
说来听听
Tell me about your dream.
一开始只是一个记忆
Well, it starts… it starts with a memory
我第一个记忆  那是我…
I think it's my first memory.
两岁大看到的景象
It's this image I have from when I was maybe two years old.
那不只是个梦?
Do you think it's just a dream?
我猜这件事发生在…
No, I think it's something that happened...
我跟我爸住的沙漠基地
when I was living at a desert base with my father.
这场梦继续下去
Anyhow, the dream goes on and...
我突然只有一个人
suddenly I'm alone.
太可怕了  我绝不会伤害你
That's terrible.You know I'd never hurt you.
小狗狗
Hey there.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name, darlin'?
你叫什么?
Eh? What's your name?
好吧  没事了
Okay.It's okay.
我们得谈谈
I gotta talk to you, Edith.
布鲁斯  留在这儿
Bruce, stay here!
C、T、G、A
C... T... G...A
G
G.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
我的布鲁斯
My Bruce.
早  葛伦来拜访
Good morning. Glen dropped by.
他跑来干嘛?
What's he doing here?
柯博士
You know, Dr. Krenzler,
我们一直没正式认识
you and I have never had the chance to get to know each other properly.
正式或非正式我都不想认识你
Well, that's because I don't want to get to know you, properly or improperly.
请你走
So leave.
我这就走
Hey, no worries.
让我先警告你
Let me give you a little heads-up.
善意收购和恶意并构
There is a hairsbreadth between friendly offer...
只有一线之隔
and hostile takeover.
我做过功课
I've done my homework.
你们的研究工作很棒
The work you're doing here is dynamite.
想想看
Think:
美国大兵拥有自我疗伤的能力
Gls embedded with technology that makes them instantly repairable on the battlefield.
专利权在我们手上
in our sole possession.
这是门赚钱的生意
That's a hell of a business.
这不是我们的目的
Well, it's not what we're doing here.
我们只是做科学研究
We're doing the basic science for everyone.
有一天我要写一本书
You know, someday I'm gonna write a book...
穷科学家的愚蠢理想
and I'm gonna call it When Stupid Ideals Happen To Smart, Penniless Scientists.
你还会再见到我
In the meantime, Bruce, you will be hearing from me.
葛伦的事…
About Glen, I, um...
没什么好说的
There's nothing to talk about.
好吧
Okay.
我只想说别担心  我会处理的
I just wanted to say, don't worry about him... I'll handle it.
怎么处理?
How?
我要打给我爸
I'm gonna call my father,
请他施加压力
ask him to exert some pressure.
你跟你爸不是不说话吗?
Last I heard, you and your father weren't speaking.
我猜我们现在有话可说了
I guess now I have something to talk with him about.
电线好像短路
I think this circuit's kinda fried.
你最好来看看
I don't know. Maybe you wanna come take a look at it.
我马上来
Okay, I'll be right there.
发射伽玛射线
伽玛射线量太高了
The gamma's too high!
我停不下来
Bruce, I can't stop it!
发射
哈普  快出去
Harper, get out!
快出来
Get out!
哈普没事吧?
How's Harper?
没事  你救了他
He's all right.You saved him.
不过他暂时不敢回实验室了
I don't think he's coming back to the lab for a while, though.
我不明白这怎么可能
I don't understand how this is possible.
你应该没命的
You should be dead.
成功了
They worked…
奈米微生物
the nanomeds.
我感觉很棒
I mean, I feel great.
它们把我的伤势治好了
I feel like... I don't know. They must have, like, fixed me.
它们杀死所有的实验对像
Bruce, they've killed everything else that they've come into contact with.
医生有没有…
Are you sure the doctor checked?
他替我做过全身检查
The doctor gave me the full workup.
他想知道我吃了什么仙丹灵药
He wants to know where he can get what I'm taking.
我的元气百分百
I'm a hundred percent.
比百分百更多
More.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
我的膝盖不是受过伤吗?
Remember my bad knee?
现在完全好了
Well, now it's my good knee.
这不好笑
Bruce, this isn't funny.
我看到你  你差点没命
I was watching you.You were gonna die,
我得眼睁睁看着你死
and I was gonna have to watch you die.
贝蒂  对不起
Betty...I'm sorry.
我是说真的
Really.
我不会爆炸啦
Hey, I'm not gonna explode. Okay?
你应该休息一下
You should get some rest.
我真的很好
And I'm fine. Really.
从来没这么好过
I've never felt better.
你的名字不是柯兹勒
Your name is not Krenzler.
是班纳
It's Banner.
什么?
What?
你原姓班纳
Your name... it's Banner.
布鲁斯班纳
Bruce Banner.
你是怎么进来的?
Bruce.How did you get in here?
我在这儿工作
I work here now.
我在实验室值大夜班
In the labs. The late shift.
这样才能接近你
It keeps me close to you.
你跟罗小姐都工作到很晚
You always work so late yourself with your friend Miss Ross.
别动  让我来
No, no. Please. Please. Let me.
你受了伤
You're not well.
你发生严重的意外
You've had a terrible accident.
你在想你为什么没死
You're wondering why you're still alive.
你身上一定有什么
You're thinking there's something inside.
与众不同
Something different...
无法解释的东西
inexplicable.
我能帮你了解它  如果你愿意
I can help you understand,if you'll let me.
如果你肯…
If you'll...
原谅我
forgive me.
这位先生
Look, mister,
我不知道我要原谅你什么
I'm sure I have nothing to forgive you for.
请你马上离开
So perhaps you should leave now.
我不会有事
I'll be fine.
你一定要知道
You must know.
也许你不信
You may not want to believe it,
但我从你的双眼看得出来
but I can see it in your eyes.
它们跟你母亲的一样
So much like your mother's.
你当然是我的亲生骨肉
Of course, you're my flesh and blood.
不过你也是别的东西
But then, you're something else too, aren't you?
你是我的儿子
My physical son,
也是我的心血结晶
but the child of my mind too.
不  你在说谎
No.You're lying.
我小时候父母就双亡
My parents died when I was a small boy.
不对
No, no, that's not true.
这是他们编的谎言
That's what they wanted you to believe.
那次实验和意外是最高机密
The experiments, the accident... all top secret.
我被关了三十年
They put me away for 30 years.
整整三十年
Thirty years!
远离你
Away from you.
远离我的工作
Away from our work.
但他们不能关我一辈子
But they couldn't keep me forever.
他们得承认我没发疯
After all, I'm sane. They had to admit it.
你要明白  这一切
You see,everything…
这些年来你费尽心思
your extraordinary mind...
寻找的东西
has been seeking all these years...
它就在你的体内
it's been inside you.
现在我们要了解它、掌控它
Now we will understand it.We will harness it.
别接  一定是罗小姐
No, don't answer it. It's Miss Ross again.
你要知道她一件事
There's something you need to know about her, Bruce.
令人不安的事
Something troublesome.
让我保护你
Let me protect you from her.
不  出去
No. Get out.
出去!
- Bruce... - Get out!
坐好
- Sit!
你最好别乱发脾气
We're gonna have to watch that temper of yours.
你真的没事?
You sure you're okay?
没事  能起床真好
Yeah, just glad to be out of bed.
我收到我爸的留言
Got a message from my father.
他要来看我
He's coming to see me.
你爸?
Your father? Mmm.
几时?
When?
他一小时后到
Lands in about an hour.
奇怪的是  他先打给我
The funny thing is, he called me.
嗨  爸爸
Hi, Dad. Hello, Betty.
哈罗  贝蒂
Here, ma'am. Thanks.
谢谢
You're welcome. Sir? Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
我就直话直说吧
Look, I'm gonna get right to it.
这跟葛伦有关  对吧?
It's about Glen, isn't it?
他鬼鬼祟祟跑来我实验室
He's been snooping around my lab.
他看到一些事
Glen noticed some things,
所以请我来收购一下
asked me to make some inquiries.
你是来质问我吗?
Are you here to question me?
不是
No.
我发现一些令人惊讶的事实
We've turned up some surprising things.
你的同事柯兹勒
This Krenzler you work with...
你知道他的真实身份吗?
you know who he really is?
你到底对他了解多少?
How much do you actually know about him?
问题是…
I think the question is,
你对他了解多少?
what is it that you know about him?
我未经授权…
- Well, right now, I'm not...
你未经授权不能向我透露
Not at liberty to disclose it to me. Right. Right.
你知道  我本来希望
You know,I think I was hoping that…
也许这次你是真的想见我
maybe this time you just...honestly wanted to see me again.
你误解了，贝蒂
You've got this all wrong, Betty.
是吗?
Do I?
是的
Yes.
我是真的想见你
I do want to see you.
我真希望能相信你
I really wish that I could believe you.
柯兹勒血液样本
这些年来你费尽心思
Everything...
寻找的东西
your extraordinary mind has been seeking all these years,
它就在你的体内
it's been inside you.
这是柯博士
Hi, you've called Dr. Krenzler.
请留言  我会尽快回电
Please leave a message and I'll call you right back.
布鲁斯  你在吗?
Bruce, hey. Are you there?
我把事情搞砸了  我爸…
Look, um, I think I screwed up.
他怀疑你做了什么
My father... It's like he suspects you of something. I don't know.
我太没耐心了  没听他说
I was so impatient, like always.I didn't hear him out. I don't know, l…
他们好像在打实验室的主意
I just think that they're planning something with the lab.
打电话给我  再见
So, um, uh...Call me. Okay? Bye.
实验室发生骚动
Dispatch! Dispatch! We have a 415 at the lab!
快派警察过来  快点!
Send Berkeley P.D. Now! Send 'em now!
发生什么事?
David, what's going on?
我们得谈谈
I gotta talk to you, Edith.
布鲁斯  留在这儿
Bruce, stay here.
我的好儿子
My Bruce.
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
实验室发生爆炸
There was some sort of explosion.
他们不让我们进去
They wouldn't let us into the building.
我很担心你
I was worried about you.
我没事
Well, I'm okay.
你昨晚发生什么事?
What happened to you last night?
我做了一场好真实的梦
I had the most vivid dream.
我就像婴儿呱呱落地
It was like being born.
探出头来透气
Coming up for air.
光亮迎面而来  我大声嚎叫
Light hitting my face.Screaming.
心脏猛烈跳动
My heartbeat…it was, like, boom…
一直怦怦响
boom...
你在实验室吗?
Were you at the lab?
不在
No.
但是有什么在
But something...
还有那个人
And there was that man.
牵着狗的那个人
The one with the dogs.
谁?
Who?
新来的工友
That new janitor.
他说他是我爸
He said he was my father.
我去开门
I'll get it.
我爸爸
My father.
真没想到
My, my.
原来你就是布鲁斯班…
So this is the young Bruce Ban...
柯兹勒
Krenzler.
昨晚你在实验室掉了东西
I think you left something in your lab last night.
米契  送我女儿出去
Mitchell.Escort my daughter outside.
我待会就来
I'll join her shortly.
我要留下来
I'd rather stay here.
快去
Now, Betty.
没关系  我没事
It's okay.I'll be fine.
看好他  我马上回来
Keep him under observation. I'll be back.
什么?
What?
你的朋友
Your friend in there.
很可能被扯进一些危险的事
There's a good chance he's caught up in some very bad business.
一些未了的事
Unfinished business.
我一定要查清楚
And I promise you, I'm gonna get to the bottom of it.
我保证会好好照顾他
You have my word I'll make sure he's cared for.
从现在起他被软禁
But as of right now, he is incommunicado.
这几天你最好离他远一点
And for the next few days at least,you're gonna stay away from here.
我这是为了你好
For your own good.
这是新工友的住址?
Okay, and that's for the new guy on the night shift, right?
太好了  感激不尽
Great. Thank you. I appreciate it.
罗博士
Dr. Ross.
真没想到
How unexpected.
请进
Please come in.
很抱歉冒昧拜访
I'm sorry to just show up at your house like this.
我是来请教一件事
I came to ask you something that...
其实我无权过问
I really have no business asking.
他跟你说了?
He told you?
他说你跟他谈过
He said you talked to him.
请坐
Please sit down.
布鲁斯昨晚在实验室
Bruce was at the lab last night.
他说你也在  他不太记得了
He said that you were there too. But he can't remember much about it.
我想知道发生什么事
I need to find out what happened.
你想知道他有哪里不对劲
So, you want to know, uh,what's wrong with him…
然后设法救他
so you can fix him?
把他治好、改变他
Cure him, change him.
我父亲是将军
My father's with the military.
他认为他对国家安全造成威胁
He seems to think he's involved in some kind of threat to national security.
你父亲… 罗斯
Your father. Ross.
你把你爸找来对付他
You brought your father down upon his head?
你什么也不懂
How little you understand, Miss Ross,
你的无知也会造成极大危险
and how dangerous your ignorance has become.
抱歉?
I'm sorry.
别道歉
Don't be sorry.
我儿子与众不同
My son is unique.
所以你无法了解他
That's why you can't relate to him.
就因为他与众不同
And because he is unique,
这世界容不下他的存在
the world will not tolerate his existence.Will they?
但是你…
But you…
你试过  对吧?
you try,don't you?
像你这种大美女
Yes.And a very beautiful woman like you,
他一定无法抗拒你的魅力
your attentions can't be completely unwanted.
对不对?
Can they?
当然不行
No.
你用水汪汪的大眼睛
Not with eyes like yours,
充满爱意地看着他
watching expectantly,lovingly.
但是想帮助他已经来不及了
But I'm afraid we're both too late to help him.
你和我都不能为他做什么
There's nothing I can do for him or for you.
而且
Besides,
他表明不想跟我扯上关系
he's made it clear he wants nothing to do with me.
这是他的选择
His choice.
恕我失陪  我要去忙了
Now, if you'll excuse me, Miss Ross, I have some work to do.
别怕那些狗  你不会有事
And don't worry about the dogs.You'll be fine.
只要你不瞪着它们
Just don't look 'em in the eyes.
再见
Good-bye.
他才出来一个月实验室就出事
He gets released, and a month later your lab is destroyed.
真是巧
What a coincidence.
告诉我他人在哪儿
So you're not gonna tell me where he is, are you?
我也很想帮忙  但我不知道
How many times do I have to tell you? I'd like to help you, but I just don't know.
你知道我是谁吧? 班纳
You know who I am. Right, Banner?
你是高阶将领  贝蒂的父亲
Your Betty's father. You're a high-ranking general.
少装了
Let's cut the crap.
我是把你爸关起来的家伙
I'm the guy who had your father tossed away, and a lot more like him,
有必要我也会把你抓去关起来
and I'll do the same with you if I feel so disposed.
是你把他关起来  别问我
You understand? If you had him tossed away, then why are you asking me?
我什么也不记得
I don't remember.
我只知道我爸死了
I was always told my father was dead.
别跟我玩游戏
Don't play with me!
你看到那一切都四岁大了
You were four years old when you saw it.
我看到什么?
When I saw what?
你也在场  怎么会不记得?
You were right there. How could anyone forget a thing like that?
什么?
What?
被压抑的记忆
Oh, some more repressed memories.
请你告诉我
Just tell me.
很遗憾
I'm sorry, son.
你的情况比我想像的更糟
You're an even more screwed-up mess than I thought you'd be.
在查清楚之前
Until we get to the bottom of this,
你的实验室成为机密军事用地
your lab has been declared a top-secret military site...
你没有资格回去
and you're not gonna get a security clearance to get back into it...
也不能到任何实验室工作
or any other lab that's doing anything more interesting than...
除非你只是研究最新草本发胶
trying to figure out the next generation of herbal hair gel.
还有一件事
One more thing.
要是你敢再靠近我女儿一步
If you ever come within a thousand yards of my daughter again,
我就把你抓去关一辈子
I'll put you away for the rest of your natural life.
乖狗狗
Dogs!
去吧
Go!
去找她
Go get her!
别让任何人挡路
And let nothing stand in your way!
快去吧
Go!
他们想用同样的方法把你除掉
So, they think they can just throw you away as they did me.
我怎么了?你对我做什么?
What's wrong with me? What did you do to me?
我今天有一个访客
I got a visit today.
不受欢迎的访客
A very unwelcome visit.
我也是逼不得已的
I'm afraid my hand is being forced.
你到底对我做了什么?
What did you do to me?
你很想知道  对吧?
You so much want to know, don't you?
但是再多的解释也比不上…
But I think no explanation will serve you half as well...
亲身的体验
as the experience.
何况我自己也不是很清楚
In any case, I still don't quite understand it myself.
当时我只想好好做实验
If they'd only let me work in peace...
他们却不放过我
Of course, my betters would have none of that.
你拿自己做人体实验
So you experimented on yourself, didn't you?
你把什么遗传给我?
And passed on to me... what?
一种改造基因
An alteration. Genetic.
我猜你可以说那是种畸形吧
A deformity. I guess you could call it that.
但是也拥有无穷力量
But an amazing strength too.
现在它被释放我就能加以利用
And now, finally unleashed, I can harvest it.
不  你不能这么做
No.You'll do no such thing.
我要把它找出来进行治疗
I will isolate it and treat it myself.
趁它没造成伤害杀了它
I'll remove it and I'll kill it before it does any real harm.
你跟你的贝蒂一定很想毁了它
I'll bet you and your Betty would love to destroy it.
但是你能毁了你自己吗?
But would you really destroy part of yourself?
应该不能
I don't think so.
至于贝蒂
And as for Betty,
我已经派我的忠犬去拜访她
I'm sending her a surprise visit from some four-legged friends of mine.
我培养了你的DNA
You see, I managed to culture some of your very own DNA, Bruce,
效果真的很惊人
and the results are tremendous.
虽然不稳定  但是力量强大
They're unstable, but very powerful.
我的DNA怎么了?
What about my DNA?
先看看贝蒂觉得怎么样吧
Let's just wait and see what Betty makes of the results, huh?
不行  你疯了  我绝不允许
No. You're crazy.I won't let you.
放开我
Get your hands off of me. Talbot, what's this...
滚进去  我要跟你谈谈
Inside, asshole. I wanna talk to you.
我父亲去找贝蒂
Listen, my father's going after Betty...
你竟敢背着我找罗斯对付我
What makes you think you can go behind my back and get Ross to cut me out, huh?
听我说  贝蒂有危险
Listen to me! Betty's in trouble!
你这可怜的怪胎
You pathetic freak.
贝蒂会被杀死
Betty's in danger.
我警告你
I swear to you, she'll be killed.
你没有资格来威胁我
I can state the obvious.Something tells me you aren't in much of a position to be making stupid threats to anyone.
陶柏?
Talbot.
干嘛?
Yeah?
你惹我生气了
You're making me angry.
是吗?
Oh, am I?
开枪!
Ohh! Oh!I got him! Open fire!
他派变种狗来找你
Bruce?He sent these dogs, didn't he?
不过我宰了它们
But I killed them!
一定是因为奈米微生物和伽玛射线
My God.It must be the nanomeds. It must be the gamma exposure.
但我们没见过这种效果
But we've never seen any effect like this before.
不  另有原因
No. Deeper.
伽玛射线触发了某种东西
The gamma just unleashed what was already there.
触发了什么?
Unleashed what?
我自己
Me.
它
It.
没事
It's okay.Shh. It's okay.
那些动物是什么?
What were those animals?
我爸派来的
My father sent them.
他真的是我爸
He is my father.
他要我改变
He wanted me to change.
他要我变成可怕的绿巨人
He wanted me to change into that mindless hulk.
为什么?
Why would he want that?
你记得什么吗?
Can you remember anything?
在你改变时?
Is there anything from when you were changed?
这就像一场梦
It was like a dream.
梦里有什么?
About what?
愤怒
Rage.
力量
Power.
自由
And freedom.
爸爸?
Hello? Sir.Hello. Dad?
贝蒂  你没事吧?
Betty! Are you all right?
我好害怕  我需要你的帮忙
I'm scared. I need your help.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
你好吗?
How are you?
还好吧
Okay,
我猜
I guess.
你的愤怒启动了奈米微生物
I think that somehow your anger is triggering the nanomeds.
怎么会?
How could it?
它们对肉体伤害才有反应
We designed them to respond to physical damage.
精神伤害也会引起生理反应
Emotional damage can manifest physically.
像是什么?
Like what?
严重的心理创伤
Serious trauma.
被压抑的记忆
Repressed memories.
你爸逼问我小时候发生的事
Your father grilled me about something that happened to me from early childhood...
他说我应该记得
that I'm supposed to remember.
是吗?
He did?
听起来很严重
It sounded bad, but...
但是我真的不记得
I honestly don't remember.
我最担心的是
The thing that worries me...
肉体伤害有限
a physical wound is finite,
精神伤害却是难以衡量
but with emotions,
很可能引起连锁反应
what's to say it won't just go on and on and start a chain reaction?
你知道我最害怕什么吗?
You know what scares me the most?
当我开始改变
When it happens,when it comes over me…
当我无法抗拒、完全失去控制
and I totally lose control,
我喜欢那种感觉
I like it.
我抱住你了  对不起
It's okay. I got you. I'm sorry.
你没事  这只是麻醉枪
You'll be okay. It's just to make you sleep.
目标倒下
Target down.
目标被捕
Target secure.
我要带你到安全地方
I'm going to take you someplace safe.Okay? Bruce?
立正
Clear!Attention on deck.
继续吧
Carry on.
他被我们埋在地底深处
We're buried out here in the middle of nowhere.
你打算把他关多久?
How long are you gonna keep him sedated?
有必要关一辈子
For the rest of his natural life, if I have to.
你说我可以相信你
You said I could trust you.
我是你父亲
I'm your father.
我会做我认为是对的事
You can trust me to do what I think is right,
而不是你要我做的事
not what you think you want.
他是个人
He is a human being.
他也是别的东西
He is also something else.
假如他逃出去
Suppose he gets out,
在大城市发飙怎么办?
has one of his little mood swings in a populated area.
我知道他很危险
Yes, I'm aware of the potential danger.
但是他也救了我一命
I'm also aware that he saved my life.
他替你痛宰一只变种贵宝狗
Yeah, from a mutant French poodle.
我真该对他感激涕零
I'm indebted to him for that.
他也把三个人打伤
He also put three men in a hospital,
陶柏也瘸了腿  你要我怎样?
and Talbot's barely walking! What do you want me to do?
我要你帮助他
I want you to help him!
你为什么这么怕他?
Why is He such a threat to you?
我了解他的出身
Because I know what He comes from.
他身上每一个分子都跟他爸一样
He is his father's son, every last molecule of him.
他说他不认识他爸
He says he doesn't know his father,
但是他们却进行相同的研究
but he's workin'in the same exact goddamn field his father did.
如果他不是说谎那就更可怕
So either he's lyin'... or it's somethin' worse,
因为他…
and he's...
怎么样?
What?
命中注定追随他父亲的脚步?
Predestined to follow in his father's footsteps?
我本来想说他受了诅咒
I was gonna say "damned."
当然了
Of course you were.
身为科学家我相信
But I'm a scientist.
我能找出原因帮助他
As a scientist, I believe we can figure this out and he can be helped.
我知道
I know you do.
不管你怎么想
Look, whether you know or care,
我都为你所做的感到自豪
I've got a lot of pride in what you've done.
但这件事太危险了
But this is too big for you.
我知道政府想利用他当武器
Look, I know the government thinks they have a weapon on their hands.
要不然他早就死了
Otherwise, he'd be dead by now.
他们大可以对他为所欲为
They can probe and prod all they want,
但是也让我帮助他
and in the meanwhile, just let me try to help him.
没有人比我更了解他
Nobody knows him better than I do.
大卫班纳对他做了什么?
What did David Banner do to him?
掩护左翼
Cover left! Clear left.
掩护右翼
Cover right!
你在干什么?
What's happening here?
我的手
My hand.
我儿子DNA的力量
You see, the strength of my son's DNA...
结合奈米微生物的再生能力
combined with nanomed reconstruction...
让我能溶入任何物体的本质
You see, I can partake with the essences of all things.
请你把手举起来
Gonna have to ask you to put your hands up, pal, okay?
慢慢来
Nice and easy.
你真以为我们是分开的吗?
Do you really believe that I am separate from you?
我在哪里?
Where am I?
你回家了
You're home.
不敢相信我们住过这儿
It's hard to believe we used to live here.
我一定见过你  甚至认识你
I must have seen you or known you.
真希望我记得起来
If only I could remember.
走吧
Let's go.
试着回想一下
Please try.
怎么了?
What is it?
没什么
Nothing.
真的吗?
Really?
该死
Damn it.
好吧
Okay, Betty...
你想知道什么?
what do you want to know?
那间房间有什么?
What was in that room?
你怕我会看到什么?
What are you afraid that I'll see?
瞧  什么也没有
See? There's nothing.
空无一物
It's empty.
我为什么不能见他?
What do you mean, I don't have access to him?
国安局决定把这个威胁
NSA has decided to turn over study of the, uh...
交给亚矽公司
the threat to Atheon.
你是基地指挥官  你能作主
But you're head of the base.I thought you were in charge.
我做不了决策  只能服从命令
But I don't set policy, and I still take orders.
我不敢相信陶柏竟然出卖我
I can't believe Talbot would go around me like this!
很多有权有势的人都想插一脚
Oh, there's a lot of powerful people that want in on this.
他们可以赚很多钱
And money to be made... lots of it.
你知道最糟的是什么吗?
You know the worst part about all this?
当我把父亲关起来把儿子送走
When I had David Banner locked up and sent that kid away,
我只把他当成一般受害者
I didn't give that boy a second thought; he was just collateral damage.
他不再是了吧!
Well, he isn't anymore, is he?
我该怎么做?
What can I do?
你该回家了
You can go home now.
我很想让你跟他道别
I'd tell you to go and say good-bye, but I've already been informed...
但是我奉命不准他和外界联系
that for now all further contact is out of the question.
是啊
Hiya,
布鲁斯  你好吗?
Bruce. How ya feelin'?
这儿的饭好不好吃?
Grub okay in here for ya?
你要什么?
What do you want?
问得好
That's a good question.
我需要你的细胞触发化学反应
See, I need your cells to trigger some chemical distress signals.
把你变成那个绿巨人
You know, so you can turn a little green for me again...
让我把真正的你大卸八块
and I can carve off a piece of the real you,
分析后申请专利赚大钱
analyze it, patent it, make a fortune.
你不介意吧?
Do you mind?
我不会让你得逞
I'll never let you.
你别无选择
I'm not sure you've got much of a choice.
你不生气吗?
Come on, Bruce. Aren't you feeling a little angry?
贝蒂弃你不顾  只有我陪你玩
After all, you've only got me to play with now that Betty's dumped you and gone back to Berkeley.
你在说谎
You're lying.
这是双赢的局面
You know, for me this is a win-win situation.
你变成绿巨人乖乖等死
You turn green, and all these guys come in and kill you...
让我进行解剖
and I perform the autopsy.
不然的话
- You don't...
我就海扁你一顿  掐断你脖子
And I mop the floor with you and maybe by accident go too far and break your neck.
这很不科学
Bad science, maybe...
但是却让我很爽
but personally gratifying.
来呀  看你有什么能耐
Come on, Bruce! Let's see what you got.
不要
Never.
你也许能用意志力控制
but subconsciously,
但是你却控制不了潜意识
I bet that's another story.
刺激他的脑波吧
All right, let's jump-start those brain waves.
亲爱的罗小姐  欢迎回家
My dear Miss Ross. Welcome back.
外面有两名守卫
There are two guards right outside.
别担心，我已经不再生你的气了
You don't have to worry. I'm not angry with you. Not anymore.
你要什么?
What do you want?
我这一生已经完了
It's over for me now. I know that.
布鲁斯也快完了
And soon it'll be over for Bruce.
所以我才来找你
That's why I've come to you...
请你说服你父亲
to ask you if you could persuade your father,
请他以一个父亲的角度考虑
as a man, as a father himself,
我愿意乖乖自首
that if I turn myself in now, peacefully...
在他把我关一辈子之前
and before he puts me away forever,
请他让我见我儿子最后一面
that he would let me see my son for one last time.
你能帮我这个忙吗?
Could you do that for me?
现在我爸也不能作主
It's out of my father's hands now.
我明白  他也成为傀儡
I understand. He's a puppet now.
-我不会怪他   -你也不应该
-I don't blame him.  -You shouldn't.
你应该对你儿子做的事情感到愧疚
You should blame yourself for what you've done to your son.
罗小姐，我对我儿子做什么了？
And what have I done to my son, Miss Ross?
什么也没做
Nothing.
我只不过尽力想改善我自己
I tried to improve on the limits in myself.
是我自己  不是他
Myself!  Not him!
你能了解吗?
Can you understand?
违反自然定律
To improve on nature.
我的自然本质，对自己的认知
My nature!  Knowledge of oneself!
这是追求真理唯一的道路
It's the only path to the truth...
让人类挣脱上帝的束缚
that give men the power to go beyond God's boundaries!
但是你不能为了自己牺牲别人
You know what's beyond your boundaries? Other people.
你只为布鲁斯带来恐惧
All you've given Bruce is fear.
对生命的恐惧
Fear of life.
恐惧?
Fear?
也许吧
Perhaps, Miss Ross.
还有孤独
And loneliness too.
两者我都经历过
Yes... I feel them both.
但是我也曾拥有幸福
But I have lived... completely once.
我深爱我的妻子
I was so much in love,
她也很想要一个小孩
and she so much wanted a baby.
我的小孩
My baby.
她一怀孕我就知道
I could tell from the moment she conceived...
那不是个儿子  是别的东西
that it wasn't a son I had given her but something else.
也许是一个怪物
A monster, maybe.
我早该结束他的生命
I should have put a stop to it right then,
但是我很好奇
but I was curious
那也是我的沉沦
and that was my downfall.
当我看着小生命逐渐成长
And as I watched this tiny life unfold,
就想到他长大后会有多痛苦
I began to imagine the horror of it,
我的好奇心被慈悲心取代
and my curiosity was replaced with compassion.
但是他们不让我治好他
But they took away my chance to cure him.
你父亲把我关起来
Your father threw me out.
那一天我记得很清楚
what are you doing?   I remember that day so well...
每一刻、每一种感觉
every moment, every sensation...
我走进屋子
walking into the house,
手里拿着刀的触感
the feeling of the handle of the knife in my hand.
我身为父亲必须结束他的痛苦
I knew I was doing a father's work, fulfilling a father's mercy.
大卫  住手
David, please stop it! No!
大卫  听我说
David, no! Talk to me! Listen!
但是她让我吓一跳
But then she surprised me.
好像…   她和那把刀
It was as if..    she and the knife...
合而为一
merged.
不
No!
你无法想像我有多绝望
You cannot imagine the unbearable finality of it.
就在那一瞬间
And in that one moment...
我夺走我所爱的一切
I took everything that was dear to me...
心中一片空虚  剩下痛苦回忆
and transformed it into nothing more than a memory.
太好了  他做了可怕的噩梦
Bingo! That must be some jumbo nightmare he just had.
动手  开始抽取酵素
Okay, do it now. Start the enzyme extraction.
刺不进去
Sir, negative on drill penetration.
那就用力  使用全力
Damn it, drill him harder! Give him full RPMs.
加油
Come on, Holeman! Come on!
杀了他吗?
Should I neutralize?
不  杀了他就没用
No! I can't do anything with goop! Come on!
把他麻醉
All right, put him to sleep.
一点都没有用
It's not stopping him!
派出我们的危机小组
Ready room, send in our containment team.
使用非致命武器
Non-lethals only. I repeat, non-lethals only.
我一定要采到他的样本
I must have a sample of him.
长官
Sir!
天啊
Jesus!
用泡沫喷他
Hit him with the foam.
强力化学泡沫
Deploy containment foam.
陶柏  快回答
Talbot, talk to me.
我控制住了  有必要再通知你
Cease fire! Under control, General. I'll let you know if we need you.
不行  我要你马上离开
Unacceptable. Unseat your asses down here immediately.
全员撤退  终止你的行动
I want a full-court evacuation now.
全面封锁
I'm shutting you down. Lockdown.
你没听到将军的话?
Didn't you hear what the general said?
我说全面封锁
I said lockdown!
让开  我要他的样本
Clear! I need a sample of him!
放轻松  老兄
Take it easy there, buddy.
这可能会有点痛
This might give you a bit of a sting here, Bruce.
退后!
Fall back! Fall back! Clear your weapon! Clear it!
退下去  给我M2弹
Give me the M2.
永别了  大家伙
So long, big boy.
立刻全面封锁
Lockdown the entire facility immediately.
全面封锁
目标移向蓝层
Target's still moving towards blue level.
把大厅疏散
Evacuate the main hall.
派人带重型武器进去，一级警戒
Send in backup, heavy weapons. Issue general quarters.
辐射污染  系统发出警讯
Contamination, sir. System readings are redline.Data's on backup power supply.
小心了
Incoming!
切断大厅电源
-Shut down all power to the main hall.   -Sir?
让他出去  到外面对付他
Show him the way out. We'll fight him outside.
停  停下来
Driver, stop. Driver, stop.
炮兵  炮管向右
Gunner, traverse left! Traverse left!
总统先生  我有坏消息
Mr. President, I have some bad news, sir.
说吧
Let's have it, General.
总统知道代号"怒汉"的事
I've briefed the president on Angry Man.
我猜是这件事吧
I assume that's what this is about.
是的
It is, ma'am.
我要求行使作战指挥权
I'm requesting a National Command Authority override.
怒汉失去控制
Angry Man is unsecure.
我要动用所有武力阻止他
I need everything we have at my disposal in order to stop his movement.
他会造成老百姓伤亡吗?
You're expecting civilian casualties, General?
我会尽全力阻止他
Not if I can help it, ma'am.
我同意  继续报告
Consider it done. Keep us posted.
通知古曼基地
Contact Goodman Control.
调派战斗直升机  连络总部
Patch data to the assets.Contact H.Q.
请他们立刻疏散
Have them initiate an immediate evacuation...
座标653-216区域
in vicinity of grid coordinates 653-216...
请确认该区完全疏散
Confirm that the area has been cleared.
该区已疏散  并锁定目标
Confirm area cleared.H.Q. Confirms area cleared. Assets on-line, sir.
各位  进攻吧
Gentlemen, it's time to dig in.
我要目标停止行动
I want this target stopped in his tracks.
天啊
Jesus.
求救!求救!
Mayday! Mayday! Ah, shit!
探戈四号被打落
Tango Four is down.
派出搜救小组
Have C-SAR respond to our 20 ASAP.
快把他引开
We're okay, but, damn it, get him off us before he tears us apart!
我打不到他  你能瞄准吗?
I've got no shot. Do you have a clear line of fire?
小心
Watch it, Tango Flight.
快向左飞
Break left! Break left!
我要发射地狱火飞弹
Tango Three, pull back and set up for a Hellfire shot.
等我们把他引开再发射
Hold your fire till we draw him off.
探戈一号准备开火
Tango One is hot. Gun wazzed.
收到  准备发射
Roger. Going hot. Guns ready.
发射飞弹
Engage at will.
退后  让我发射
Tango One, pull back! Clear my line!
让开  我瞄准目标了
Tango Flight, clear back.
好了  开火吧
Tango One, Tango Three. I have contact.
我射中他了
I've got him painted for Hellfire.
天啊  他接到我的飞弹
Holy shit! He's got my missile!
求救!
Mayday! Mayday!
求救  我被击落了
Mayday! Mayday! We're hit! We're going down!
有没有人伤亡?
Give me a head count.Tango Three, give me a sit rep.
直升机被击落  无人伤亡
Our kite's busted up, but we're okay.
你们看到目标吗?
Tango Flight, do you have eyes on the target?
他在岩石堆
Tango One. I have him in the rocks.
全力开火  把它移为平地
Salvo all. Turn it into a parking lot.
它被移为平地了
T-bolt, your parking lot is ready.
油量不够  返回基地
We're bingo for fuel and ammo. R. T.B.
指挥官  目标没被摧毁
T-bolt, this is Goodman Control.Be advised, target not destroyed.
他又在移动
He's on the move again.
可恶
Damn!
找到他了
I've got it.
看来他要回家
It appears he's heading home.
出动战机  拦截目标
Launch fast movers.Have them intercept and engage.
布鲁斯逃出来了
Betty, Bruce got out.
他往你那儿去  大概是去找你
He's headed your way and probably right for you.
你离基地多远?
How far from the base are you?
我到了  他们把他爸带来
I'm already here. They're taking his father in now.
这是好消息  待在那儿 贝蒂
That's all good news. Stay there, Betty.
旧金山柏克莱
传奇一号和二号急速接近中
Legend One rolling in hot. Legend Two breaking off left.
我要折回来进行攻击
I think I can come back around for a gun attack.
瞄准目标就开火
Acquire a clear target. Fire at will.
是民航机  快爬升
Increase altitude. Civilian aircraft in vicinity.
快拉高  你会撞到大桥
Pull up! Pull up! You're headed for the bridge!
我拉不高
I can't pull up! I can't pull up!
把他载到大气层外
Okay, you've got him now. Take him on a ride to the top of the world.
让他吸不到空气
Let's see what the thin air will do for him.
启动后燃引擎
Initiating afterburner.
爬升到六万英尺高度
I'm passing flight level 600.
我到了极限
This is out of my envelope.
撑着点
Hang in there, Legend.
他抓得太紧  无法维持高度
I can't maintain. He's all over my aerodynamics.
他会比你先昏过去
He'll lose consciousness before you.
九万五千英尺
Nine-fifty.
我撑不下去了  我要下降
I can't hold it. I'm pulling back!
卑微的人类
Puny human.
他坠入大海  准备开火
Contact. He's in the water. All units, weapons hot.
不能冒险  全力开火
Let's not take any chances.You are cleared to fire on target, Legend.
我别无选择  一定要消灭他
Dad? Betty?We don't have a choice.I have to destroy him.
你不能这么做
But you can't.
把他激怒只会让他更强壮
You will only fuel his rage, and you will make him stronger.
他是去找你的
It's you he's coming for. You know that.
那就让我去找他
Then let me go to him.
求求你
Please.
给他机会冷静下来
Just give him a chance to calm down.
旧金山领空的民航机
All aircraft vicinity of San Francisco, this is T-bolt on guard.
这区域是飞行禁区
This area has been declared restricted airspace.
所有飞行物必须立刻撤离
All aircraft are ordered to clear the airspace immediately.
锁定目标  准备开火
Echo, One-niner. Weapons are hot.
等待攻击指令
Target acquired. Waiting your orders to engage.
准备开火  等候指令
Repeat, waiting your orders to engage.
所有单位，停止开火
All units, hold your fire.
这里是指挥，所有单位停止射击
This is T-bolt to all assets. You have
direct orders to holdyourfire.
重复一遍，停止射击
I repeat, holdyour fire.
你找到我了
You found me.
你并不难找
You weren't that hard to find.
我很难找
Yes, I was.
大家听好了
Let's take a walk.
他要留在基地
That's the deal, gentlemen. He stays on this base...
直到我接到命令再处置他
until we get the final word from C-3 on how to dispose of him.
要是他敢轻举妄动
In the meantime, if he does anything but sit there in that chair,
就开启电源把他烧焦
we're gonna turn on the juice and he'll be incinerated immediately.
建立两百码的保护范围
We've established a 200-yard perimeter, sir.
要是启动电磁波
If we deploy the electromagnetic array,
应该不会伤及无辜
there should be no collateral damage.
我是为了你才这么做
I'm doin' this for you, Betty.
但是我们要有最坏的打算
But one way or another, we're gonna have to prepare for the worst.
我应该杀了你
I should have killed you.
我也早该杀了你
And I should have killed you.
真希望你杀了我
I wish you had.
我昨晚看到她
I saw her last night.
我看到她的脸
Saw her face.
棕发
Brown hair.
棕眼
Brown eyes.
她对我笑
She smiled at me.
低下头亲我的脸颊
She reached down and kissed my cheek.
我几乎能闻到她的味道
I can almost remember a smell.
就像沙漠花朵
Almost like desert flowers.
她最爱擦的香水
Her favorite perfume.
我连我妈妈的名字都不知道
It's my mother, and I don't even know her name.
没关系  尽管哭吧
It's all right, son. You go ahead and cry.
大声地哭吧
Go ahead and cry.
哭一哭对你也好
Cry. Crying will do you good.
别碰我
Don't touch me!
也许你以前是我父亲
Maybe once you were my father,
但是现在和以后都不是
but you're not now and you never will be.
是吗?
Oh, is that so?
让我告诉你
Well, I got news for you.
我不是来见你的
I didn't come here to see you.
我是来见我的儿子
I came here to see my son.
我真正的儿子
My real son.
在你体内的东西
The one inside of you.
你只不过是一个空壳子
You're nothing but a superficial shell,
你薄弱的意识
a husk of flimsy consciousness...
在一瞬间就会消失殆尽
ready to be torn off at a moment's notice.
随便你  我不在乎  快走吧
You can think what you like. I don't care. Just go!
听我说  我找到解药
No, son. Listen to me. I found a cure.
治好我的解药
For me.
我的细胞也能突变
My cells can transform too,
吸收大量的能量
absorb enormous amounts of energy.
但是却不稳定
But, unlike you, they're unstable.
儿子  我需要你的力量
Son, I need your strength.
我赐给你生命
I gave you life.
你该给我回报了
Now you must give it back to me!
比以往强大一百万倍
Only a million times more radiant, more powerful!
住手
Stop it.
为什么?
Stop? Stop what?
你想想外面那些穿军服的人
Think about all those men out there in their uniforms...
只会盲目地服从命令
barking and swallowing orders,
以武力统治全世界
inflicting their petty rule over the entire globe!
他们造成了多大的伤害
Think of all the harm they've done!
对你!对我!
To you! To me!
对全人类!
To humanity!
我们可以让他们的国旗、国歌
And know this... that we can make them...
和他们的政府永远消失
and their flags and their anthems and their governments disappear in a flash!
只要你我合而为一
You in me.
我死也不肯
I'd rather die.
这就是你的回答?
Oh, that's your answer?
那你真的应该死后重生
Then indeed you shall die... and be reborn...
成为在文明污染人类灵魂之前
a hero... of the kind that walked the earth...
傲视地球的英雄人物
long before the pale religions of civilization infected humanity's soul!
滚!
Go!
别哭了
Stop your bawling,
你这没有用的人渣
you weak little speck of human trash.
我这就走
All right... I'll go!
你就看着我走吧
- You just watch me go! - Hit it.
通电
Hit it.
再试一次
- Hit it again!
不行  没电了
We can't, sir. There's no power. Some kind of counter-electromagnetic field.
有一股逆向电磁场
Move in and assault the target. Move in!
摧毁目标  快去
Move, move, move!
我找到他们  在梨子湖
Sir, I've located them on radar. Pear Lake.
通知伽玛弹小组
Call up the task force.
很好
Yes!
这就对了  继续抗拒
That's right. Keep fighting.
你越抗拒我吸收的能量就越多
The more you fight, the more of you I take.
奇怪
Strange.
温度急速下降
We're reading a phenomenal drop in temperatures there.
同时有放射性活动
But simultaneous radiological activity.
他们在吸收周围的能量
They're absorbing all the ambient energy.
沉睡吧   布鲁斯 遗忘一切
Sleep now, Bruce, and forget forever.
别再挣扎了
Struggle no more...
把力量全都给我
and give me all of your power.
你承受得了就拿去吧
You think you can live with it? Take it!
全都拿去
Take it all!
很好  很好
Oh, yes! Yes!
拿回去
Take it back!
停不下来了
It's not stopping!
快拿回去
Take it back!
各位  发射伽玛弹
Gentlemen... release.
发射伽玛弹
Gamma charge away.
祝好梦
- Mwah! - Sweet dreams.
一年后
-你好  -贝蒂?是你吗?
Hello? Betty, is that you?
嗨  爸
Hi, Dad.
很高兴找到你
I'm glad I caught you.
很高兴你打来
I'm glad you called.
谢谢
Thanks.
贝蒂  你跟我…
Look, Betty... you and I...
我们都知道布鲁斯活不了
well, we both know that Bruce couldn't have survived that blast.
不过要是你…
But... well, you know...
怎么了?
What is it?
你也知道  世上有很多疯子
Well, you know.The usual loonies. Seein' things.
他们到处都看到绿巨人
Only now everything's green.
是啊
Right.
听我说
Look, uh...
要是他真的没死
if by some chance he did survive...
当他试着跟你联络
and he should try to contact you, try to get in touch,
你会告诉我吧?
you'd tell me, wouldn't you?
我不会
No... I wouldn't.
我也不需要
But you know as well as I do, I wouldn't have to.
我的电话被窃听、电脑被监控
I mean, my phones are bugged, my computer's tapped.
一举一动都被监视
I'm under surveillance.
老实说
I'll tell you, though,
假如他还活着
that if he were alive,
我最不希望他来找我
I'm  the last person I would want him to come to...
尽管我很想他
because... as much as I miss him,
我...我...我爱他
I... I... Ioved him.
贝蒂，我很抱歉
I'm sorry, Betty.
我非常抱歉
I am so sorry.
我知道
I know you are.
听爸爸的话乖乖吃药
[Man SpeakingSpanish ]
把药都拿走
闭嘴
坐下来
这些药是给当地居民的
你懂个什么屁?
他们在帮助敌人
也许你也一样
通通拿走
这全是政府的
你惹我生气了
你不会喜欢看见我生气的样子的！